["Flower Ring" by Shino Shimoji
and Aya Suzaki plays]
- Spring passed us by,
and the sun began shining down
stronger each day.
The vegetables look brighter
and more colorful
after they've been
sunbathing for a while.
[Hiraku sighs]
Hey, girls.
- Huh?
- [Hiraku] It's break time.
Let's have lunch.
- Yay!
- Okay.
- Let's go.
- [Sena] I'll get
everything ready.
- I'm starving.
- Thanks.
Hmm.
This one might grow
too tall like this.
I feel like I'm much more
knowledgeable about this stuff
than when I first
started farming.
Let's see about
the other plants.
- [Lu] Darling.
- Oh.
Huh?
Lu?
- Come on, it's time
for a break.
[gentle music]
- [Beast Girl]
Well, did you remember
to bring the silverware?
- You know, Hiraku,
you need to take breaks too.
- Huh?
When I look at the crops,
I can't help myself.
- Mm.
- Hmm?
[Lu giggles]
Magic really is great.
- I've told you,
this is just basic stuff.
[Hiraku sighs]
- I feel refreshed.
- If you work too hard,
your body could collapse.
- Don't worry, I'll be fine.
But more importantly,
is it okay for you
to be walking around?
- Yeah, I'm okay now.
In fact, I've heard it's
good to get exercise.
- [Hiraku] Is that right?
- [Lu] Everyone's been
teaching me all kinds of stuff.
- [Sena] I heard from
the girls in the village
that it's important...
- [Lea] Reproduction
and prosperity.
- [Sena] to exercise
to keep your body strong.
- After speaking with a few
of the ogre maid girls
I found out that they've
actually given birth themselves.
- That's reassuring.
- Yeah.
- I don't know anything
about that stuff.
It's strange to think that she
has a child inside her belly.
I wonder what that
must feel like for her.
- So what is it actually like?
Now that you've gotten so big,
it's got to feel heavy.
- It does.
It feels the same as
two heads of cabbage.
- I'm guessing that means,
you must feel pretty heavy then.
- How lovely,
I'm so very jealous.
- I wonder if it'll be a boy
or maybe a little girl.
- Is there any way
to know that now?
- Is there anything we can do
to make you more comfortable?
- Please let us know how best
we can help you, Lu.
- Thank you.
You've all been so helpful
so I'm okay.
My appetite is back now too.
The only thing bothering me is,
- [All] Hmm?
- that I can't drink
any alcohol.
- [All] Oh.
- [Granmaria] Mayor.
- Oh.
- Forgive our insolence,
but we have come to make
a request of you today.
- [Hiraku] Okay. What is it?
- We are here to ask that Tia
and everyone else's
resolution not go to waste.
- They've become so dejected.
[Latismoon and Hakuren groaning]
- We beg of you.
So please,
sell off all the rest of
the alcohol in the village.
- Huh?
I see you're all giving up
alcohol for Lu.
- That's right, however...
- When we think about not
being able to drink we just...
- [Hakuren] When we're
eating we think,
"Man, some alcohol
would go great with this."
It feels like...
[all whining]
Just like that.
- [Hiraku] It's that bad?
- I believe at this point,
the only option is to
remove the source.
- Calm down.
I'm happy that you're
all doing this,
but I think you'll regret it
if we sell all the alcohol,
and alcohol isn't something
we can make quickly.
Just think of it
this way instead,
the taste of alcohol changes
the longer you let it age.
If you hold out now,
it'll taste better later.
Let's all tough it out while
looking forward to that.
- Forgive us, Mayor,
but we'd like for you to tell us
if we've done something
to wrong the village.
- Why? What happened?
- Even though everyone used
to love drinking alcohol,
none of them will drink
a single drop now.
- [Hiraku] Oh.
- Really? So that's all it was.
So it's not like they
stopped enjoying
the alcohol we produce.
- Of course not.
I'm sorry, we should have
told you right away.
- I was beginning to think
that we should slow down
production.
Now I think the opposite.
- You're right.
They'll drink more to
make up for lost time.
- [Donovan] Great, we'll do our
best to live up to expectations.
[gentle serene music]
[Daga sighs]
[water splashing]
[wind blowing]
- You feeling okay?
- Yeah, I'm fine.
I'm not in here because of that.
It's just the sun is
really strong today.
- [Hiraku] It's almost time,
isn't it?
- It looks that way.
If I get any bigger than this
I won't be able to move at all.
- Where'd you get that?
- Tia and the angels came
to visit me and brought it.
They said they found it blooming
on a far away mountain
where there was still snow.
- [Hiraku] It's pretty.
It kind of makes
the room feel cooler.
- Believe it or not
that flower is actually
releasing cold air.
- Hmm, pardon?
- [Both] Hmm?
- This is secret
mountain elf medicine.
It brings about good health
and vigor, for you.
- [Lu] Oh, this is really
valuable, isn't it?
- I'd rather it be used
at the right time
than have it just sit around
in storage forever.
- [Hiraku] It sounds like
she's talking
about a rare game item.
- Hi, Lu.
This gem is meant to help
with magic recovery.
I found it in my father's
treasure room.
- Oh, wow.
- After much work,
it's finally perfected.
I made pudding.
- Mm.
- Here.
It's a good luck charm wreath.
[Lu giggling]
- Are you okay? Do you want
me to peel you apples?
- Good afternoon.
You must be hungry.
I made tomato and tofu miso soup
- Tomato?
- [Lu] Mm.
- [Hiraku]
It's surprisingly good
- [Flora] Isn't it?
- All lizard men are
born from eggs.
Therefore, I have absolutely
no idea how best to help out.
But at the very least,
I offer my blood to drink
so that you'll grow stronger.
- [Lu] I don't think that my
teeth can make it through that.
- [Daga] Aw...
[lively upbeat music]
- [Hiraku] I'm really happy.
- Yeah.
[both chuckling]
- What's this?
A mallet?
- It came from Donovan.
He said to trust him that it
would come in handy one day.
- Hmm.
Come in handy?
Do you need a mallet
for childbirth?
Huh?
What's wrong?
- Mm.
My belly feels kind of...
- Does that mean?
- Mm.
I think that it's time.
- Bring the towels here.
We need to boil more water.
Here's some more wood.
[maids panting]
[footsteps echoing]
[Lu groaning]
[gentle serene music]
- [Hiraku] When the time came,
I found myself in
a panic for a bit,
but now there's nothing left
that I can do to help out.
[gentle serene music]
[wind blowing]
[footsteps echoing]
[gentle serene music]
The two moons.
On my first night here,
I watched them from
this very place.
Back then, I was alone.
I wanted to live somewhere by
myself away from everyone,
but now everyone's here.
That's why I am sure that...
After that time passed
like a blur until morning.
Well, it's more
accurate to say
that I don't have any memories
of what happened after that.
- Mm.
- Everything went really great.
- Mother and baby
are doing very well.
[Hiraku gasps]
- Come hold him.
- Can I really?
I, um.
- Be careful.
- He was just born,
watch his neck.
- Make sure to support it
with your arm.
- Okay.
[gentle spirited music]
He's warm and he's
heavier than I expected
even though he's so small.
Oh, he moved.
- Of course he moves, you silly.
He was moving when he
was still in my belly.
- Oh, I see.
Ah, he smiled.
That was a smile, right?
- He must be really happy
that his dad's holding him.
- Oh.
Oh, that's right.
I've really become a father.
Back in my original world,
I was suffering from an illness.
I hope he never has to
go through that.
Grow up to be big and strong.
- He's not going to just
grow up strong.
We'll raise him to be
strong together.
- That he will.
[baby crying]
What's wrong?
What should I do?
- [Sena] Please calm down.
- [Lea] Everyone, just relax.
- [Lu] It's okay.
[Hiraku chuckling]
[bright upbeat music]
- [Hiraku] All done.
It's been a week since
Lu gave birth.
My son's name is Alfred.
That was Lu's idea.
I guess his race is technically
maybe half vampire,
but right now he still looks
like a normal human.
[everyone gushing]
This is where I started
living by myself.
A lot more people live here now.
There are more
buildings now too.
Everything kept growing.
Now it's a village where I live
together with everyone.
Then one day,
I became mayor,
and now I finally
become a father.
Speaking of which,
I need to do something
to thank the villagers
for their kindness.
They've all been working
so hard up until now
to help build up the village.
Hmm.
- Oh, what did you want
to talk to us about?
- The thing is,
I've been thinking about a
new system I want to set up.
- [Tia] A system?
- That's right.
Like this.
It's a reward medal.
- A medal?
- I see, what is it for?
- As thanks for helping
to build the village.
I want to give these medals
out to everyone.
- So then how exactly are we
supposed to use these?
- You can trade them
for goods you want
or use them to get other
things you're after.
- So you mean these act like
a money exchange, right?
- Yeah.
I figured that one day
this village
will need its own currency.
Right now we have a lot
of stuff in the village.
Crops, hunted game meat,
and traded goods.
As mayor of the village,
I've been taking charge
of all these things
and then distributing
them to everyone myself.
Whenever someone
wants something,
they come and ask me about it.
But with the increasing
population here,
handling all of
these transactions
has become impossible.
- I see.
If we're going to handle
transactions on our own
then we need currency.
- [Hiraku] That's right.
- Can't we just all trade
goods with each other?
- Think about it this way.
How many strawberries
for an apple?
- Well, I'd say three
strawberries.
- I'd say they're one to one
since I much prefer
strawberries.
- See?
Everyone has their
own idea of value.
That's why I want to
use currency
for all our
transactions.
- So that's what money
is meant to be used for.
- [Hakuren] How many barrels
of gold is an apple worth?
- [Latismoon] I almost never
use money so I'm not sure.
- You count it in barrels?
- I expect nothing less
from the dragons.
- Anyways, it would
cause turmoil
if I switched us
to currency right away.
So for now, I'm going to
give these out as rewards.
That's the plan.
- I see then.
Well, in that case,
let's try them out
for a while.
- Sounds great.
For now, let's just think of
these as convenient vouchers.
And so to get things going,
I started by giving all the
villagers three medals each.
I couldn't give out medals
to all of Kuro and
Zabuton's families,
so I gave them 30 each.
On top of that, I have to
make them all by hand
in a way that they can't be
counterfeited.
That limits how many I can make.
Everyone reacted differently.
- [Donovan] Give me wine.
[dwarves laughing]
- [Hiraku] Some people traded
them for wine right away.
Some people traded them
for furniture and the like.
Some traded them for weapons
that Dryme had brought us
as gifts.
And some people just decorated
their rooms with them.
I'd prefer if they didn't
just hold onto them
without spending any.
That's how I started
introducing the medals
that were the precursors
for currency, but let's see.
Oh, I've got it.
It resulted in orders
for custom made furniture
and toys to become
incredibly popular.
If anything, I feel like
I'm doing more work now.
Just wait a little while for me.
I wanted to use these
as a guide
for how much things are worth,
but it's hard to determine
how much a single medal
should be worth.
- [Beast Girl Kid] Mayor!
- [Both] Oh?
- I want you to give me...
a baby just like that one!
- Is that an option?
- [Hiraku] It's not!
- What if I give you three?
- That's not really the issue
we're having here.
[Lu chuckles]
[children laughing]
- [Hiraku] In the end,
we settled on them renting out
the mayor for a day instead.
And a little while after that,
[villagers chattering]
it was finally time
for the big feast
to celebrate the birth
of my son.
- [All] Cheers!
[cheerful festive music]
- I feel kind of bad.
I kept them waiting a while.
- Yeah, we couldn't have a feast
right after you gave birth.
Well, they all seem to be
enjoying themselves now.
I am a little worried that they
might drink too much though.
- Hi there!
It's your Aunt Flora!
- By the way, is that?
- It is.
Donovan told me to bring it
here with me today.
- Sorry we took so long.
- [Hiraku] What's this?
- It's a special
new kind of wine
that we made just for you
to have tonight.
This is our way of
celebrating with you
so make sure you do it right.
It's time to whack it!
- Oh, you mean this?
- I see, so that's
what it's for.
- [Both] And smash!
[everyone cheering]
[cheerful festive music]
[Lu chuckling]
- That felt really good to hit.
- Yeah, it sure did.
I never thought I'd be
cracking open a barrel of wine
in celebration in this world.
I guess doing something big
like this
always makes things more fun.
Hey guys, drink up!
[cheerful festive music]
- Man, this booze is great.
The food is great,
congratulations.
Now time for my
secret technique.
- Is she okay there?
- Well, what do you
think of the wine?
- Donovan?
- Well, the thing is...
- Hmm?
Ah, I get it.
- I'm sorry.
I've been told I shouldn't
drink while breastfeeding.
- [Donovan] I see.
You can't drink as long as
he's still a baby.
I get it.
- Right now, I'll let
them drink for me.
I'll enjoy the wine by watching
all their smiling faces.
- I've got an idea.
How about before
everyone drinks it all?
We bottle it so we can age it.
- That sounds great.
We can hold it until Alfred
is old enough to drink it.
- Great idea.
- All right.
I'll keep it safe and age it
so it's the best wine ever.
Get started on this right away.
If we drag our feet,
they'll drink it all.
- I want more.
- The day I drink with my son...
I can't hardly wait for that.
- That day will be soon.
As long as you're enjoying life
every day like this.
- [Flora] Look.
- [Both] Hmm?
- Alfred, the sweet
little dumpling,
loves his Aunt Flora so much.
I think he wants to be my baby.
- Stop right there
- [Beezel] About the
Great Tree Village.
- [Grattz] What is it this time?
- [Beezel] The mayor
and vampire had a child.
It was a healthy baby boy.
- [Grattz] Oh, that's lovely.
- Based on the information
we've heard so far,
I think the very notion
that we could challenge them
is near impossible as of now.
- [Beezel] So you finally
realized it.
- We should be thinking
how we can maintain
an amicable relationship
with them,
and if we could marry off
someone from the kingdom
to their village, then it would
guarantee our safety here.
- [Galgardo] No way.
- What?
- I won't hand over Yuri.
Not to anyone ever.
No matter what!
- [Beezel] Please calm down.
- [Michael] Did you gather
all the goods?
- [Employee] Yes.
- It'll leave a poor impression
if we don't congratulate
them properly.
We must make sure our
preparations are perfect.
I want our relationship with
that village to continue.
[bright gentle music]
[cow mooing]
[wolf barks]
- [Tia] Is something the matter?
- [Hiraku] No, it's nothing.
I just had a dream for
the first time in a while.
[children laughing]
- Could it be that you
have a hangover?
- But you didn't drink
last night either.
- You're right, I'm fine.
- Oh, good.
- Hmm?
- In that case, I wanna
talk about something
that Granmaria and
the others brought up.
- [Hiraku] People that
want to move here?
- Yes.
They were all living in
a different forest,
but now they're looking for
somewhere new to live.
- Dryme has some people that
were driven out of their homes
because of a war.
- My father also mentioned
that there are some refugees
that need a place to stay
because of a war.
- How many are there?
- It's not exact, but...
- Um, let's see.
- A rough estimate.
- We broke the three digit mark.
I think we need another
village like this
if we're going to take
that many people
- Well, then let's do it.
- Huh?
- Let's build a new village
for all the people that
want to move here.
- Ah, that sounds great.
- If we do that, then lots of
people can move here.
- It'll be the
Great Tree Village Two.
- Wait a minute now.
Won't that be a ton of
work for everyone?
We need to gather supplies.
- [All] We'll do our best.
- After all, this village saved
each and every one of us.
- If someone is needing our help
we can't just leave them alone.
- [Flowrem] Still, we'll need
to plan everything out
very carefully for this.
- [Lea] Where should
we build it?
- [Hiraku] All right,
let's meet on it now.
I'm counting on
your help everyone.
- [All] Yeah.
["Feel the winds" by
Yui Hizuki plays]